JIACHENG SHEN

Ph.D Student, The Chinese University of Hong Kong Email: jcshen@cse.cuhk.edu.hk, Tel/WeChat: (+86) 135-1213-8818

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Jiacheng's research interests span memory systems, distributed systems, and cloud computing. Specifically, he is devoted to building high-performance and resource-efficient cloud storage systems using modern and emerging hardware, *e.g.*, disaggregated memory. His recent work focuses on improving the efficiency and reliability of storage systems on disaggregated memory. During his Ph.D. studies, he has already published 9 papers in major conferences and journals in the areas of computer systems and software engineering, including SOSP, OSDI, FAST, ASE, ICDCS, DSN, etc.

EDUCATION

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Hong Kong SAR, China 2020.08 – Present

Ph.D in Computer Science and Engineering

- ARISE Lab, Computer Science and Engineering Department
- Supervised by Prof. Michael R. Lyu (IEEE fellow and ACM fellow)

Fudan University

Shanghai, China

BSc. in Computer Science

2016.09 - 2020.06

• Overall GPA: 3.78/4.0; Ranking: 1/155

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Huawei CloudShenzhen, ChinaResearch Intern2021.09 - Present

- Research on replication protocols for storage systems on disaggregated memory.
- Construct an adaptive caching framework for storage systems on disaggregated memory.
- Integrate disaggregated memory into Redis.

Fudan UniversityShanghai, China
Research Assistant
2020.08 – 2021.07

- Tracing and debugging for RDMA-based distributed systems.
- Mitigating cold starts for serverless platforms.

MicrosoftShanghai, ChinaSoftware Development Intern2019.10 - 2020.01

- Data analytics for maintaining Dynamics 365.
- Develop visualization and deployment tools for Dynamics365.

HONORS AND AWARDS

National Scholarship

Fudan University 2019

Scholarship for Outstanding Students

Fudan University 2017 – 2020

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Jiacheng Shen, Pengfei Zuo, Xuchuan Luo, Yuxin Su, Jiazhen Gu, Hao Feng, Yangfan Zhou, and Michael R. Lyu. Ditto: An Elastic and Adaptive Memory-Disaggregated Caching System. In 29th ACM Symposium on Operating Systems Principles (To appear), SOSP 2023, CCF-A.
- 2. Jiacheng Shen, Pengfei Zuo, Xuchuan Luo, Tianyi Yang, Yuxin Su, Yangfan Zhou, and Michael R. Lyu. FUSEE: A Fully Memory-Disaggregated Key-Value Store. In *21st USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies, FAST 2023*, **CCF-A**.
- 3. Xuchuan Luo, Pengfei Zuo, Jiacheng Shen, Jiazhen Gu, Xin Wang, Michael R. Lyu, and Yangfan Zhou. SMART: A High-Performance Adaptive Radix Tree for Disaggregated Memory. In 17th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation, OSDI 2023, CCF-A.
- 4. Jiacheng Shen, Tianyi Yang, Yuxin Su, Yangfan Zhou, and Michael R. Lyu. Defuse: A Dependency-Guided Function Scheduler to Mitigate Cold Starts on FaaS Platforms. In 41th International Conference on Distributed Computing Systems, ICDCS 2021, CCF-B.
- 5. Tianyi Yang, Jiacheng Shen, Yuxin Su, Xiaoxue Ren, Yongqiang Yang, and Michael R. Lyu. Characterizing and Mitigating Anti-patterns of Alerts in Industrial Cloud Systems. In 52nd Annual IEEE/IFIP International Conference on Dependable Systems and Networks, DSN 2022, CCF-B.
- 6. Tianyi Yang, Jiacheng Shen, Yuxin Su, Xiao Ling, Yongqiang Yang, and Michael R. Lyu. AID: Efficient Prediction of Aggregated Intensity of Dependency in Large-scale Cloud Systems. In 36th IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering, ASE 2021, CCF-A.
- 7. Tianyi Yang, Baitong Li, Jiacheng Shen, Yuxin Su, Yongqiang Yang, and Michael R. Lyu. Managing Service Dependency for Cloud Reliability: The Industrial Practice. In 33rd IEEE International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering Workshops, ISSRE 2022 Workshops, CCF-B.
- 8. Shuyao Jiang, Jiacheng Shen, Shengnan Wu, Yu Cai, Yue Yu, and Yangfan Zhou. Towards Usable Neural Comment Generation via Code-Comment Linkage Interpretation: Method and Empirical Study. *IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering, TSE 2023*, **CCF-A**.
- 9. Tianyi Yang, Cheryl Lee, Jiacheng Shen, Yuxin Su, Yongqiang Yang, and Michael R. Lyu. An Adaptive Resilience Testing Framework for Microservice Systems. In *arXiv preprint*, 2022.